<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>launchd on deanishe.net</title>
    <link>https://www.deanishe.net/tags/launchd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in launchd on deanishe.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 01:21:30 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.deanishe.net/tags/launchd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Auto-swap day/night Alfred themes</title>
      <link>https://www.deanishe.net/snippet/auto-swap-alfred-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2016 16:32:05 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.deanishe.net/snippet/auto-swap-alfred-theme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Swap Alfred theme at sunrise and sunset. Goes well with &lt;a href=&#34;https://justgetflux.com&#34;&gt;f.lux&lt;/a&gt;
and macOS&#39;s night mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It uses &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.launchd.info&#34;&gt;launchd&lt;/a&gt; to call itself at sunrise and sunset (or
as soon thereafter as your machine boots/wakes), and tells
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.alfredapp.com/&#34;&gt;Alfred&lt;/a&gt; to change its theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-none&#34;&gt;toggle_alfred_theme.py [-v|-q] [-d|--dark &amp;lt;theme&amp;gt;] [-l|--light &amp;lt;theme&amp;gt;]

    **You must first edit this script (or the accompanying bash wrapper)
    to set your location!**

    These scripts (Python script and bash wrapper) live at:
    https://gist.github.com/deanishe/ce442c3a768adedc9c39

    Change Alfred&#39;s theme depending on whether it&#39;s dark outside. Theme
    is changed immediately when the script is run and the script will
    also call itself again at sunrise and sunset (via launchd) to change
    Alfred&#39;s theme. It&#39;s works well together with F.lux, which can
    switch to Yosemite&#39;s dark mode at sunset.

    Just run the script *once* with your preferred themes:

        python toggle_alfred_theme.py --dark &#39;Dark Theme&#39; --light &#39;Light Theme&#39;

    or if you&#39;re using the wrapper:

        toggle-alfred-theme.bash --dark &#39;Dark Theme&#39; --light &#39;Light Theme&#39;

    and it will ensure Alfred&#39;s theme is changed every day at sunrise
    and sunset.

    To change your preferred themes, just run the script again.

    Note: Because the script calls itself via launchd, if you move the
    script, it will stop working until you run it again.

Usage:

    toggle_alfred_theme.py (-h|--help)
    toggle_alfred_theme.py --timezones
    toggle_alfred_theme.py (-t|--times)
    toggle_alfred_theme.py [-n] [-v|-q] [--dark &amp;lt;theme&amp;gt;] [--light &amp;lt;theme&amp;gt;]

Options:
    -h, --help           Show this help message
    -n, --nothing        Show what would be set, but make no changes
    -t, --times          Show sunrise and sunset times for next 7 days
    --timezones          Show a list of (&amp;gt;500) supported timezones
    -l, --light &amp;lt;theme&amp;gt;  Alfred theme to use after sunrise
    -d, --dark &amp;lt;theme&amp;gt;   Alfred theme to use after sunset
    -v, --verbose        Show debugging info
    -q, --quiet          Only show warnings and errors

Installation &amp;amp; Setup:

    This script requires the `astral` and `pytz` libraries. Install with:

        pip install astral

    It&#39;s better to install them in the same directory as this script (or
    use a virtualenv), in order not to muck up your Python installation
    or break other software:

        pip install --target=/directory/where/this/script/is astral

    Adjust the settings at the top of this script in the CONFIG section
    (or in the bash wrapper) to match your location.

    `TZ_NAME` must be one of the timezones recognised by `pytz`. To see
    a list of all supported timezones, run this script with the
    --timezones option. (Note there are over 500 timezones.)

    You can usually find your town&#39;s latitude, longitude and elevation
    on its Wikipedia page.

How it works:

    When run, the script will immediately set Alfred&#39;s theme according
    to whether it&#39;s light or dark out, then tell OS X to run the script
    again at the next sunset/sunrise. Even if your computer is off/asleep
    when the script is supposed to run, it will be run immediately on
    boot/wake.

    Note: Yosemite has some issues with running LaunchAgents on wake. If
    the script isn&#39;t running when it&#39;s supposed to on Yosemite, but the
    script reports the correct times, it&#39;s a problem with Yosemite, not
    this script.

    The script has to fork into the background (i.e. exit successfully
    immediately) because `launchctl` doesn&#39;t like the script updating
    the Launch Agent while it&#39;s running it.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two files, the Python script and a bash wrapper. The wrapper&#39;s
only purpose is to store your configuration, so you can upgrade the
Python script without having to edit it again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You &lt;strong&gt;must&lt;/strong&gt; set your location in one of the scripts before usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can usually find the latitude, longitude and elevation of your town
on its Wikipedia page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script type=&#34;application/javascript&#34; src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/deanishe/ce442c3a768adedc9c39.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>